MIKE FREESTONE

WEB DEVELOPER

mikefreestone@gmail.com 416-666-0350 linkedin.com/in/michaelfreestone github.com/freestonemike

PROFILE

It was in my first and only coding class while studying video game development in college that I realized I loved to code. I finally made the leap to formally pursue a career in Web Development by enrolling in a Diploma program. I've learned, through managing large teams in the restaurant industry, how to approach a problem and efficiently plan to solve it. Now I'm ready to combine my experiences to help businesses solve their online needs.

SKILLS

Javascript, HTML5, CSS, React.js, DOM APIs, Node.js, Express.js, Web APIs, User Authentication, OAuth, GitHub, MySQL, JEST, Enzyme, Animation, Illustration

EXPERIENCE

Senior Inventory Analyst | Sculpture Hospitality

MAR 2020 - NOV 2020, TORONTO, ON

- Revitalized client relationships by setting up personalized consultations to identify specific needs.
- Authored a weekly client breakdown for the Regional Manager, and analysed reports orally in week-end meetings.
- Designed best practices for our Data Collection team, decreasing audit errors by over 50% average per week.

Marketing Specialist | Sotheby's International Realty Inc.

MAY 2018 - JAN 2020, TORONTO, ON

- Planned and executed a marketing strategy, resulting in the highest personal sales year for 1 agency broker.
- Collaborated with an outside Web Development organization to launch a new website for a Senior VP.
- Fielded lead inquiries to identify individual needs and qualify them for the next steps with the broker.

Manager | Restaurants & Bars, Sheraton Centre Toronto

MAR 2012 - AUG 2015, TORONTO, ON

- Transformed an underperforming business unit by better aligning the Food & Beverage team.
- Awarded the "most improved" department title in Q4 2013 for increasing YoY sales and employee engagement.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma Candidate, Web Development

JAN 2021 - APR 2021, TORONTO, ON

Durham College | Diploma, Game Development

SEP 2008 - APR 2010, OSHAWA, ON

PROJECTS

Toronto Raptors Pre-Game Segment | Lead Creator

DEC 2020 - JAN 2021, SPORTSNET Animation / Illustration

 Created an animated illustration that was aired Nationally during the Toronto Raptors Pre-Game Show. (https://bit.ly/20fntQt)